BRAULIO ARREDONDO

+34692-317-295

braulio.arredond@gmail.com \diamond GitHub \diamond LinkedIn \diamond braulioarredondo.com

OBJECTIVE

I'm a certified Cloud Engineer with 6+ years of experience in AWS, CI/CD, IaC and Microservices. Highly skilled software developer in Python, Deep Learning, Machine Learning and Data Science. Currently, orchestrating and automating cloud solutions for digital automation and energy management.

EXPERIENCE

Lead Cloud Operations Engineer K-LAGAN

Jun 2024 - Present Remote

Cloud Operations Engineer for a multinational cooperation specialized on digital automation and energy management with presence in more than 100 countries.

- More than \$10k USD saved per month by optimizing production and lower environment snapshot policies.
- More than 100 cloud based servers migrated for major Linux updates.
- Technical Level 2 and Level 3 help desk support for more than 50 development and service teams around the world.
- Resource administration for more than 500 accounts spread around the world including EC2, EKS, S3, ELB, CloudFront, IAM and many others.
- Resource deployment for development solutions trough automation tools like Ansible, GitHub actions and Terraform.
- Monitoring and maintenance activities to guarantee high reliability and availability monitoring for thousands of critical servers, applications and services placed on cloud.

Skills: CI/CD · Terraform · Ansible · Troubleshooting · LogicMonitor · Monitoring · Infrastructure as code (IaC) · Amazon Web Services (AWS) · Python · Veeam · Kubernetes · Linux · Github · Automation · Dynatrace

Cloud Operations Engineer @ Southwest Airlines Softtek

Feb 2021 - Jun 2024 Remote

AWS Cloud Services Administrator, Site Reliability Engineer, Python Developer and Incident Troubleshooter for more than 500 cloud accounts of the world's largest low-cost carrier. Daily activities consist in dev operations, API development, pipeline automation, cloud support and monitoring.

- Selenium automated smoke test for 36 End User Authentication endpoints.
- AWS AHA module for events delivery on ServiceNow dashboard.
- Grafana monitoring dashboards for AWS TGW and AWS DX traffic.
- Python onboarding library for Nexus and artifact pre-validation job for Gitlab CI/CD
- 50 hours saved annually by building Gitlab CI/CD pipelines to query and delivery 20 AWS and cloudability resource mapping reports.
- 20 hours saved annually by building an AWS Application for intelligent Jenkins volumes management and deletion.
- 20 hours saved annually by building a Gitlab CI/CD pipeline to query, delete and reuse Atlassian App's user licenses using AWS SSM documents and SQL.
- Gitlab CI/CD integration test pipeline used by a TLG with more than 100 Distributed Deployment Engine Projects.

Skills: $CI/CD \cdot Terraform \cdot Cloudformation \cdot Troubleshooting \cdot API Development \cdot Monitoring \cdot Infrastructure as code (IaC) \cdot Amazon Web Services (AWS) \cdot Python \cdot Docker \cdot Kubernetes \cdot Grafana \cdot Jenkins \cdot Gitlab \cdot Automation$

Jr. Research Fellow CONACvT

Jan 2019 - Dec 2020 Monterrey, Mexico

Funded Jr Researcher for a cloud classification project of breast, colon and lung cancer histopathological images using Deep Learning and Machine Learning techniques. Project developed using Python, Pytorch, Keras, Pandas, Sci-Py and Scikit-learn, performed on Google Cloud and AWS services. More than 95% of accuracy for tissue classification using Keras CNN. More than 90% of accuracy for tissue classification using 5 computer vision techniques and 10 ML techniques.

- More than 95% of accuracy for histopathological tissue images using Keras CNN.
- More than 90% of accuracy for histopathological tissue images using 5 computer vision techniques and 10 ML techniques.
- 10 Google Cloud automated playbooks and jobs for image cropping and classification.

 $\textbf{Skills:} \ \ \text{Convolutional Neural Networks} \cdot \text{Machine Learning} \cdot \text{Google Cloud Platform (GCP)} \cdot \text{Deep Learning} \cdot \text{Python}$

EDUCATION

Master of Science MS, Computer Science, Tecnologico de Monterrey

Grade 9.6/10

Member of the Bioinformatics Research Group, CONACyT Full-ride Scholarship Award

Bachelor of Information Technology, Universidad de Guanajuato Outstanding Student Award

Grade 10/10

LICENSES & CERTIFICATIONS

DevOps with Docker, University of Helsinki, Certificate ID: 56c728eb326ae

Containers, K8s and Istio on IBM Cloud, IBM, Badge ID: wlkiAn4i

AZ-900: Microsoft Azure Fundamentals , Microsoft, Certiport ID: wNJYM-2FqG

AWS Certified Developer Associate , AWS, Badge ID: 378dfe4dc1e1

AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner, AWS, Badge ID: bef76c68e394

AWS Knowledge: Networking Core, AWS, Badge ID: 448b199a57de

Google Grow: Cloud Computing, Google, Certificate ID: DS8 4NF NY8

PUBLICATIONS

Histopathological Image Classification using Deep Learning (Nov, 2021) (repositorio.tec.mx)

This thesis presents a study of digital pathology classification using and combining several techniques of machine learning and deep learning.

A Further Search for Galactic Stars with Double Radio Lobes (Jun, 2017) (arxiv.org)

Further search for double-lobed radio stars in two samples of spectroscopic stars: over 20,000 white dwarves from the Sloan Digital Sky Survey and 2.5 million stars from the Large Sky Area Multi-Object Fiber Spectroscopic Telescope.